Their only weapon is the truth.
5 Days of War is a war, drama film directed by Renny Harlin.
An American journalist and his cameraman are caught in the combat zone
during the first Russian airstrikes against Georgia.
Rescuing Tatia, a young Georgian schoolteacher separated from her family during the attack, the two
reporters agree to help reunite her with her family in exchange for serving as their interpreter.
As the three attempt to escape to safety, they witness--and document--the devastation from
the full-scale crossfire and cold-blooded murder of innocent civilians.
Thomas Anders, played by Rupert Friend.
Tatia Meddevi, played by Emmanuelle Chriqui.
Sebastian Ganz, played by Richard Coyle.
Miriam, played by Heather Graham.
Capt. Rezo Avaliani, played by Johnathon Schaech.
Col. Demidov, played by Rade Šerbedžija.
5 Days of War is a 2011 war film directed by Renny Harlin.
The story is about the Russo-Georgian War over the Russian-backed breakaway autonomous republic
of South Ossetia in Georgia, including the events leading up to the conflict.
The film was released in Georgia as 5 Days of August, and in other
countries as 5 Days of War and also City on Fire.
The film explores themes of journalist, war crimes,
mass murder, evacuation, interpreter.
The tone is emotional.